It's great to meet you.
Great to meet you as well.
Who am I here with today?
Reid Hoffman.
And what was your business?
I'm the co-founder of LinkedIn.
You co-founded LinkedIn?
Yes.
What was the most amount of
money you made in a single year?
When I sold LinkedIn to Microsoft
and we sold it for $26 billion.
You sold LinkedIn for $26 billion?
Yes.
They think it's one of
the best acquisitions they've ever done.
And was it worth it for them?
It was worth it for them
and it was worth it for me.
And you started LinkedIn in 2003.
Yes.
Did you have a lot of people that
doubted you when you first started that business?
Oh yeah.
No.
More than two-thirds of my smart friends thought I
was going to be a complete failure with LinkedIn.
Actually?
Yes.
Why did you not listen to them?
Well, you do.
You want to go to
people and you want to say,
what's wrong with my deal?
Why would it fail?
And then what do I know that they don't know?
Because a VC looks at 600 to 800 deals a
year and says yes to zero to two of them.
So why would they take a bet on you?
When I met with the Airbnb co-founders,
I told them in two minutes I was
going to make them an offer to invest.
So if you had to start from zero and
you had one year to make a billion dollars
and your life depended on it, what would you do?
Guys, this is about to be one
of the craziest videos that I've ever done.
I'm about to go meet up with and
interview my 18th billionaire that I've ever interviewed.
And it isn't just any ordinary billionaire.
It's Reid Hoffman, the founder of LinkedIn.
And he sold his company
LinkedIn to Microsoft for $26 billion.
$26 billion with a B.
And Reid invited us out to
Los Angeles to come interview him,
to figure out what it takes
to become a billionaire in today's world
and how he became one of the
most influential tech moguls of all time.
So let's waste no more time.
Let's go.
Let's go meet up with Reid and
go see what he has to say.
All right, you guys, we just got to our destination
where we're going to be linking up with Reid Hoffman
and getting a billion dollars
worth of game for you guys.
Come on, let's go.
Hi, Adam.
It's great to meet you.
Great to meet you as well.
Thank you for having us out to do the interview.
My pleasure.
I really appreciate that.
Who am I here with today?
Reid Hoffman.
And what was your business?
I'm the co-founder of LinkedIn.
You co-founded LinkedIn?
Yes.
In what year?
But AI startups now.
So you're getting into AI right now.
Yeah, well, I've been in AI since
I led the first round in OpenAI.
So I've been in AI a bit.
So let's go back to those
early days when you're building LinkedIn.
What was that initial moment that
you knew that this was the thing
that you were going to go all in on?
What was that first moment
building LinkedIn when you knew that,
okay, I'm burning the boats.
We're going all in on this thing right here.
Well, actually, because I'd learned
from social, PayPal, et cetera,
you burn the boats early.
You don't get confidence and then burn the boats.
You go.
Why do you say that?
The key element of risk is
take a risk that other people
won't take that might fail.
But if you win, you win huge.
You weren't afraid of failure, though.
No, but everyone's a little afraid of failure.
But I knew that I could
survive failure, that I could play again.
That's the key thing is make
sure that you can play again.
So how did you find yourself
believed to go make billions of dollars?
I think it was that I had a
good sense of I knew what strategic game
I was playing and I
knew I could play multiple times.
And I knew that doing software things within Silicon Valley
was a very good place to be doing it.
If I was in New York,
I might have been doing something else,
finance, et cetera.
If I was in LA,
I might have been doing media.
But like, no, no, this is
the place where you can do software.
You sort of linked it in 2003.
Yes.
Was that during a time where a
lot of people were doubting the fact
that those social networks would
actually be prevalent years from then?
Well, everybody in Silicon Valley
thought the consumer internet was done.
It was only like Amazon and
Google and PayPal and so forth.
And then actually, in fact, they
thought it was enterprise software and cleantech.
So it's like, oh, no, the Internet's over.
And by the way, what
are you doing this business thing?
Is that like Friendster, but for business?
What is that?
So you had a lot of people
that were telling you, no, I'm sure.
Oh, yeah.
No, more than two thirds of my
smart friends thought I was going to be
a complete failure with LinkedIn.
Actually, yes.
Why did you not listen to them?
Well, you do.
You want to go to
people and you want to say,
what's wrong with my idea?
Why will it fail?
So they give you permission to do that.
And then what do I know that they don't know?
Because if you have a good theory of that,
that's the chance that you
might have something that's really amazing.
So what was it that
you knew that they didn't know?
The most common feedback was a network property.
First person in, no value.
We know each other now, no value.
We already know each other.
So no value, no value, no value.
How does the thing ever grow?
And I knew I could get it
to grow even when people didn't actually,
in fact, have any value
in the system at the beginning.
You come from a family of entrepreneurs?
No, actually, I came from a family of civil servants.
So like my grandfather was like,
wait, why has he become an industrialist?
This is terrible.
So what was your turning point to entrepreneurship then?
Like who was the most influential,
most inspirational person on you that enabled you to build
one of the most influential
tech companies in the entire world?
So what I decided, I went to Stanford University,
majored in AI.
And what I decided was
I wanted to create new products.
And that led me into entrepreneurship.
I initially went and worked at
Apple Computer and Fujitsu and other things.
And I was like, no, no,
I want to create a new product.
And that's the thing that led me.
Throughout your career,
what was the most amount of money
that you've made in a single year?
One of the things that's
amazing about having co-founded LinkedIn
is last year it did $16 billion in revenue.
LinkedIn did $16 billion last year?
Yes, yes.
How much did you sell LinkedIn for?
We sold LinkedIn for $26 billion.
To who?
To Microsoft.
What was that conversation like?
How did you exit LinkedIn
for over $20 billion to Microsoft?
That's incredible.
Well, so what happened is Satya Nadella, Bill Gates,
came down the office and said, we're interested.
I was like, well, okay, let's talk about it.
They think it's one of
the best acquisitions they've ever done.
Was it worth it for them?
It was worth it for them
and it was worth it for me.
What's your secret to networking
with other billionaires like Bill Gates?
Let's say somebody doesn't have a ton of credibility.
Before you had all the credibility that you had,
how did you build those relationships with those A players
that were able to take you
places that money can't take you?
Guys, this interview with Reed has been amazing so far.
We're about to get right back to it,
but I've got a very
special announcement to make real quick.
See, 99% of people will
never get mentored from a multimillionaire
or a billionaire in their entire life.
And you guys are always reaching out to me,
asking me how I'm able to connect with and interview
and build relationships.
With the most successful and the
wealthiest people in the entire world.
And see, every single month,
I give you guys direct access
to four of the millionaires
and billionaires that I interview
inside of my private entrepreneur community.
But here's the thing.
I'm turning 23 years old this week on May 10th.
And for that reason, I'm going
to give you guys direct access
to not four, but seven of the multimillionaires
and the billionaires that I interview on this channel,
including the CEO of a publicly traded company
that sold his first business
to Oracle for over nine figures.
And I'm going to give you all that.
Direct access to seven millionaires and billionaires
on live calls for just $23.
I've never done anything like this before,
but since it's my birthday, I
want to give back to you all.
This is your chance to speak directly to the millionaires
and billionaires that I
interview and get personalized advice
and one-on-one mentorship from them.
Whether you're stuck in a nine to five
and you want to learn
the exact steps that it takes
to leave that job and start building
and creating the business of your dreams,
or maybe you've already taken that leap,
that risk and started that business,
but you want to learn
from the most successful business owners
how to start scaling and making your first six,
seven, or even eight figures at your business,
then this is your opportunity to join
and become a member of the number one community
for business owners in the entire world.
But here's the thing.
You only have from now, you're watching this right now,
until the end of my
birthday on May 10th at midnight
to join and become a member for just $23.
Because after that, at the end of my birthday,
it goes back up to 50.
So to join now and become
a member of the School of Mentors,
the number one community for business owners
in the entire world,
go down to the link in
the description of this video to join.
I can't wait to see you on the show.
I'll see you inside.
With that being said, let's get back to the interview.
You created the biggest social
networking platform in the world.
What's your best networking advice for anybody in business?
The key thing is think what you can give someone.
So what's something that you
could do that would help them?
So for example, Satya Nadella started calling me
because I'm like, oh, here's what you need to understand
about Silicon Valley.
And he's like, that's really helpful.
That helps me as Microsoft engage with Silicon Valley.
And similar, when talking to Bill, I don't say,
hey, Bill, you're just so great.
He is great.
But it's like, oh, here's something that's going on
in the modern world of tech.
Like, here's something about AI.
That I see that you may not have seen yet.
So has Bill Gates become a friend of yours?
Yeah, Bill's great.
What do you notice about these people?
Among the most successful people that you've gotten
to know really well, what
do they all have in common
that's enabled them to be part of that 0.00001%
of the top 1%?
Well, there's three different things I'm going to say.
I'm going to give you three.
So one is curiosity.
So like intensely wanting to learn.
That's like Satya, Bill.
Another one is just raw grit.
And kind of like, I am
going to make this work, right?
This is a whole stack of different people.
But like, for example, Patrick Collison,
or others.
Then the last one is kind of understanding,
what do I understand about the world
that other people don't understand?
And that's a little bit like, for example,
frequently Peter Thiel is the contrarian hypothesis.
You think a lot of networking is bullshit?
The networking is bullshit that's kind of like,
hi, I'm Reid.
Here's my business card.
The thing that's real is forming connections
where actually, in fact, we are really helping each other.
What's the biggest mistake you see people make
when they are trying to network
with other successful people?
They ask for something versus offer something.
So it's like, hey, what can you do for me?
That happens all the time for people.
It's like, no, no, here's something
that could be useful to you.
And by the way, maybe you're wrong.
Maybe it's not useful.
Fine.
But when it is, you get attention.
You get the beginnings of a relationship.
You were talking about two-thirds of the people
that have told you no in your network.
Yes.
You were part of the PayPal mafia.
Can you explain what that
is to people that don't know?
I always say PayPal network, but PayPal mafia is sexier.
So people really go with it.
And it's basically the crew of people
who turn PayPal from an encryption system
on mobile devices to a worldwide payments network.
You were a huge role in PayPal getting acquired
for $1.5 billion from eBay.
What's your best negotiation advice
for any entrepreneur in business right now?
You've been at the table with some very heavy hitters.
Give me your best negotiation advice
for anybody in business.
So the way we're going to think about it is
companies are bought, not sold.
So if you're selling, you have a problem.
You want them to come in and buy you.
So the question is, how do
you get that to be their idea
that they are coming to buy you?
I hadn't heard that perspective before,
that they're bought, not sold.
Yes.
How did you get in that mindset shift?
Well, because part of the
thing is, it's like the dynamic.
If you show up, just like
you show up to a venture capitalist
and you say, hey, I'm trying
to sell you on this thing,
then the person kind of rolls back and like,
okay, now this is me being powerful.
You're trying to sell your company.
Where it's like, oh, well, I
could be selling to somebody else
and I've got this thing that I'm doing.
And it's like, no, no, I want that.
You have to think of the psychology of the person.
So I want you to think back to you
throughout your career real quick.
What is the best advice
you ever got from a mentor?
So weirdly, it's from my dad.
And it was when I was in high school.
He said, the difficult thing about making decisions
is that you reduce opportunity in the short term.
Because when you make a decision,
you've chosen door A and not door B.
But it's the only way you
get opportunity in the long term.
And what's the most difficult decision
you made that paid off?
Oh, wow.
Probably starting my first company
is social net.
And by the way, social net didn't pay off,
but it got me into the journey of doing it.
How did you deal with that adversity?
Because a lot of people, they see social media nowadays
that it's all glitz and glamours and entrepreneurship.
But you had some adversity.
You had some failures at the beginning.
How did you overcome that?
How did you learn how to pivot?
Well, what you want to be doing is saying,
I'm not just playing a one-time game.
I'm playing a multi-time game.
And I'm expecting that I'm
going to fail along the way.
Some.
Because it's not that you want to fail.
It's not that you celebrate failing,
but you celebrate learning in order to win.
I'm going to have you dig
deep on this one right here.
I'm going to ask one more piece of advice
that you got from a mentor.
Give me one from the dad.
Give me one from somebody
in that network that you had
that really changed your life from a business standpoint.
Well, when someone actually tells you something
that you really need to hear
that wasn't something you were originally planning.
So I was networking my way to VCs early.
And one of the lawyers
that I actually talked to said,
hey, look, you're a friend of Lori's.
Let me just tell you,
you're not going to be
able to raise money right now.
You need to go prove your credentials
at launching products first.
Go do that first.
Then go try to raise money.
And that's what I went.
I actually went and ended up working
at Apple Computer Year World.
And then built a network around me.
And that helped me.
Did you take on a lot of capital to scale?
Well, in today's term, de minimis.
But it was $5 million in the first round.
Nothing after that?
Oh, no, no.
Ultimately, we raised about $140 million.
What was your secret to raising capital?
It's one of the hardest
things for business owners to do
because investors, they invest in people
and they invest in businesses, not ideas, right?
So the best thing is,
think about what kinds of things investors look.
Investors are looking for something
that's going to be amazingly big.
And they're looking for things that they think
is the current trend for what's going.
So like AI, things are good to pay.
Although if you say, hey, it's an AI milkshake,
that won't work so well.
So you're looking for that.
And then you're looking for,
why is it you're going
to take a bet on me?
So like a VC looks at
600 to 800 deals a year
and says yes to zero to two of them.
So why would they take a bet on you?
And being edgy that way is really helpful.
So what's the number one thing that you look for
in a business or a person
when you're deciding to make an investment?
As somebody who's been one of the most successful VCs
in the game.
It's being surprised about something
that could be amazing.
So like for example,
when I met with the Airbnb co-founders,
I told them in two minutes,
I was going to make them an offer to invest
because they had gone,
we've seen something no one else has seen,
which is eBay, but for space.
And here we go.
What's your most contrarian opinion
about the future of industries
that venture capital will be investing in
that maybe a lot of
people will disagree with you on?
Probably that the world of bits
will be greatly accelerating the world of atoms.
So part of the reason
why I just co-founded a company
curing cancer with AI
is because AI will accelerate how we discover new drugs.
That acceleration will also be like,
for example, robots,
that acceleration will be manufacturing.
Like we will figure out how to build much better,
cheaper, faster houses because of AI.
What's the most common mistake
you see business owners make in today's world?
You became one of the
most successful VCs in modern time.
You've been on the board
of a lot of successful companies.
What's a blind spot that a lot of,
maybe even successful founders have
that you see across a
lot of companies in today's world?
It depends a little bit on which game you're playing,
but within the tech startups,
it's not taking the bold enough risk.
You're trying to make sure that you're successful
versus, hey, I'm going to try this
and either it's going to be
spectacular or I'm going to die.
And that's okay if, or I'm going to die.
You wrote a book called Blitzscaling.
What is the most effective way to scale fast?
The important thing to do when you're scaling,
blitzscaling, going really fast,
getting your company large, attacking a market,
is to say, how do I make decisions
in a way that I do
not take my foot off the accelerator?
It's like when you're driving, you say,
am I going to get off this thing or not?
The time that I can make the decision
is by going full speed ahead.
So you say, hey, should I go into this market?
Should I launch this product?
Should I hire this person?
Well, what's the way that I do that?
Not ever slowing down.
Now, a lot of entrepreneurs,
the reason why they struggle to scale
is they want to be that solopreneur.
They want to wear all the hats themselves.
Who is the most important to hire in any business?
So one of the things that's most important to hire
or partner with are the people who add their strengths
against your weaknesses.
So for example, I'm a creative problem solver.
That's really good.
I need people who run
like all the trains on time,
who are very operationally tight and buttoned down.
And so you're looking for the person
who is a right partner for you.
How important is vertical integration
to whatever business somebody's involved in?
Well, it's important to know what game you're playing.
And if the game is vertical integration,
then do it well.
One of the things I got,
I thought we would have individual subscriptions
as the primary business initially,
and it was enterprise.
And you pivoted.
And the way we learned it is we said,
look, when we launch individual subscriptions,
we had companies coming to us saying,
we'd like to buy.
And we're like, huh, the companies are coming to us.
Customers are coming to us.
All right, make a slide deck, complete image,
and send it out saying,
this is the product we're building.
The sales guy came back with purchase orders.
And we're like, okay, we're building that product.
How old are you now?
I'm 57.
How old were you when you became a billionaire?
Probably 38, but I'd have
to really go look at it.
So if you had to start from zero
and you had one year,
to make a billion dollars
and your life depended on it,
what would you do?
Do something that's very different
than what other people would be doing.
Now, there's a lot of AI stuff right now,
but what would be something that would be,
I mean, I started a cancer drug discovery company,
but that's not a year.
That's like five, 10 years.
So do you think in decades then?
Oh, yeah.
I almost never play a one-year game.
I play a 10-year game.
Why is that?
Because part of, again, where it's contrarian
is most other people don't think about 10 years.
They don't think about how you compound to 10 years.
And compounding to 10 years
is one of the things that gives a differential edge.
But even if you've already had an exit
for over $20 billion,
you still are still thinking that long-term.
Yeah, absolutely.
Why is that?
Like, just because?
Well, because that's actually how you create something
that's epic, that changes industries.
And looking back to that exit,
what was the number one thing
that led to an exit over $20 billion?
It was a realization that building a network
and getting growth in the network
and then monetization could come later.
So like frequently when people think of business,
they think, well, I gotta
have someone pay me right now.
It's like, no, no, no, no.
Actually, like, build the network
and then the business will
be built on top of it.
So was the grind to become
a billionaire worth it for you?
Yes.
But also,
not just the money,
it's the changing the world through the product.
One more message for the younger generation
aspiring to become successful
and a self-made billionaire like you.
Life is a team sport,
not an individual sport.
Pick your team.
I love it.
Reid, thank you so much, my friend.
Really appreciate you.
This is awesome.
Guys, this interview with Reid Hoffman,
the founder of LinkedIn,
the multi-billionaire,
was incredible.
But I need you guys to like and subscribe
for amazing content
we've got coming every single week.
And like I said earlier, you guys,
you can right now join the number one community
for business owners from now
until the end of my birthday
on May 12th.
And you can get content that midnight
for just $23
and get access to seven of the multi-millionaires
and the billionaires that I interview on this channel
for the month of May
and literally get mentored from them.
You guys, there is nothing like this
that exists anywhere else in the entire planet.
Only at the School of Hard Knocks
and inside the School of Mentors.
So I can't wait to see
you on the inside of the community.
Go down to the link in the description to join.
With that being said,
I'll see you in the next video.